This video is about how to get help when
learning to use R and taking this course.
Because of the, because of the size of the
course and the number of students that are
enrolled it's going to be difficult to
have, to
be asking lots of questions on a
one-to-one basis.
And so we're going to have to resort to a
few other tools to get questions answered.
In particular, the discussion boards and
generally through e-mail.
And so, there's a certain type of way to
ask questions that will kind of, that will
hope
to maximize the chance of you getting the
right answer or the answer that you're
looking for.
And so at, the main thing to remember is
that asking questions
via email is, is a little bit different
from asking questions in person.
You don't necessarily know that the people
on the other
side, the people that you're asking, for
example, on the discussion
board or on a mailing list, have, you
don't necessarily
know that they have the same background
information that you have.
furthermore, they may not know you
personally, and so may not know your
kind of, what you mean when you say
certain types of things.
so, that's kind of important to keep in
mind when you are
e-mailing questions as opposed to when
you're talking to someone in person.
Keep in mind of course that elder people
are very
busy and their time is limited and
although may be willing
to help you by answering a question, they
may have only
a certain amount of time to devote to
answering that question.
Now, I am here of course to, a the
Instructor, to help you in
all circumstances but furthermore, I may
not
be able to answer all possible questions.
And so you want to, you're going to
want to, use the
resource that you have available to you in
this course.
So in your search for answers there are a
variety of things that you
can do on your own before venturing off to
other people for the answer.
So if you are going to be emailing a
question to a forum or
to a mailing list, it's importnat that you
search the archives of that forum for
the answer.
So, it's possible, and depending on the
size of the forum, almost
very likely that that someone has asked
the same question that you're asking.
And if someone else has asked that
question and it has been
answered then the answers giong to be in
the archives for that forum.
So if the answer's already there you save
everyone a lot of time, including
yourself, if you search the archives for
that forum and just find the answer.
Of course the web is very large and has
many answers and your first reaction
when you have a question is to search the
web.
for, given the type of program you're
using, for example, here we're using R,
there are many manuals that are available
and many answers may exists in the manual.
There's a frequently asked question, a FAQ
that's
on the R website that you can look for,
that contains many questions that are
commonly, come up
up on the mailing lists and on the forums.
Another thing that you might want to try
to do before you go venturing out
to ask people the, for the answers, is to
play around with the problem and
try to find the answer by inspecting or
experiment, experimentation.
So maybe if you have a function that's not
working right, maybe change the
inputs and see, see if the outputs change,
or if the error message changes.
if, if you're lucky enough to have a
skilled friend
who knows something about R, you can ask
them personally.
And it will be easier to, it's usually
easier to ask a person on
a one-to-one basis than to email a group
of people in a, in a forum.
furthermore, then lastly, if you're a
programmer you
may be able to find the answers you're
looking for by reading the source code.
So, all of the things on the previous
slide are, are useful
things to do on your own before venturing
out to ask people questions.
However, if you don't find the answer
it's, it's important to let other
people know that you did all those other
things on the previous slide.
Because if, for example, the answer is in
the
documentation, for the program, for
example, it's in one of
the R manuals then someone who knows the
answer
will usually respond by saying, read the
documentation or read
the manual.
Ad then you've just wasted one round of
email because they'll have to
respond saying I did read the manual and I
didn't find the answer there.
And so if you, letting people know that
you've done all, you've done your homework
and you've,
you've looked in a variety of places, is
very useful and it saves a lot of time.
So here's a just a very simple example of
what might happen as you're using R.
So here I'm loading the data sets package.
And then I'm going to load the air quality
data set
from that package.
And then I'm going to want to run the
correlation function on this air quality
data frame.
So immediately I get an error.
It says error in core, air quality missing
observations in cov slash cor.
So you might be wondering well why am I
getting this error?
What does it mean?
So the first thing you can do is go to
Google.
And in many circumstances Google is going
to be your friend.
And this is no different when you are
learning
a new programming language or when you are
learning R.
And so the easiest thing to do is, is to
take the error message
that you get and literally cut and paste
it into the search box for Google.
When I search on that I get a number
of results, and particularly this third
result looks very promising.
It looks like someone asked this question
on the R help mailing list and it looks
like and so maybe, maybe we're clicking
that
to see, if someone replied with the
answer.
So, when you ask a question on a mailing
list, so assuming that
Google wasn't able to help you out you're
going, if you're going to ask
a question on a discussion board or on the
mailing list, there are
a couple of things you need to think about
before you ask that question.
First, is it possible to reproduce your
problem?
So, is it, so when, if someone else can
reproduce your problem, it makes it
a lot easier for that other person
to figure out what the solution's going to
be.
And so if you can provide some
code or some very simple example that will
reproduce your
problem, this will be enormously useful to
everyone else involved.
And if you don't do this typically the
first response
you get will be can you please provide a
reproducable example.
Second it's important to understand what
you
expect the output to be, because if your
expectation is wrong, then of course your,
it may or may not be an error depending
on what your expectation should be.
So what you expect the output to be will
indicate kind of how,
what the nature of the error and what
needs to be solved.
And then, given your expectation, you'd to
say, what do you see instead?
So what was the thing that was unexpected
that gave you the question?
Other information that's important to
specify when you're asking
a question, is the version of the product
you're using.
For example what version of R are you
using?
What version of the R
packages are you using, if it's specific
to a given package?
Because often there may be legitimate bugs
and versions and older versions of R or R
packages and that the your problem might
be
solvable if you just upgrade to the latest
version.
So, if you're using the latest version of
R it's important to mention that.
Sometimes it's important to know what
operating system you're using, so whether
you're
using a Mac or Windows or Linux or some
other Unix machines, it.
Some problems can be traced
to the type of operating system that
you're using.
And depending on the question that you
have, there
may be additional information that you
need to provide.
So, when you send an email to a forum or
to a discussion board.
It's important to get as much information
in
there, as much useful information in there
as possible.
And, this includes the subject line for
the email.
So there's a couple of examples of subject
lines that kind of range in usefulness.
So, that is probably the least useful,
just says, help, can't fit linear model.
So, here there's, there's very little
information here.
All I know is that there's something,
there's some problem
with linear models I don't know anything
else about what the user's problem is.
So the second version is is, is much
better.
Eh, it tells me that on R version 2.15.0
the lm() function produces
the seg fault which meaning that R
crashes, with a large data frame.
And it furthermore says I'm using Mac OS
10 10, 10.6.3.
So here I've got the operating system, the
version of the operating system, I've got
the
version of R, I've got what function I'm
using,
and I've got a summary of what actually
happened.
So, just a little bit smarter than that
would, would just be to
reformat the message so that I specify
what version I'm using the function and
then the version of the operating system
and then, and then, so that
gives me the context and after that I can
say what the problem was.
In this case it was the seg fault on a
large data frame.
So, here the
important details are right away put into
the subject header
before I even get to the body of the
message.
So, a couple of things that you definitely
want to do when you're asking a question
on a forum or a mailing list first is to
describe the goal, not the step.
So, you may have many, many steps that
you're going
through and maybe one of those steps is
causing a problem.
And it's useful for other people to know
what your big, what
the bigger picture is in terms of what
you're trying to do
because, for example, they might have a
better idea about how to
go about achieving that goal, which may be
faster or simpler and
may work around whatever problem you're
having.
So describe the ultimate goal and then
talk about what the problems are.
And don't just narrow it down to the, to
the one little step that you're having a
problem with.
Be explicit about your questions, so
remember,
provide details about what you're trying
to do.
And you have to provide the minimum amount
of information necessary.
So not the maximum amount of information,
the minimum amount of information.
And so it's common
to see see on some mailing list posts
that, you know, lots of outputters
produce, and
that's not very helpful, because volume
doesn't really
help you in terms of diagnosing the
problem.
We need to know exactly, to narrow down
kind of where the problem is going to be.
So, and of course, a couple things, you
know, being courteous never hurts anyone.
And it and promoting civility on mailing
lists is always a nice thing.
And if you find the solution later on,
it's useful for everyone
else in the community if you follow up
with the solution and explain
what the problem was, what the problem was
and how you solved it.
A couple things you definitely do not want
to do when posting to a forum.
You don't want to claim that you found a
bug.
This happens all the time and usually, I'd
say 99 times out of 100, it's not a bug
and it's just a misunderstanding about
what should have
happened, so a mistake in the expectation
of the user.
Groveling as a substitute for doing your
homework, that's not
usually looked well upon and you
definitely shouldn't do that.
Definitely don't want to
post homework questions on a mailing list
or forums and,
and the reason is because people who write
the homeworks,
the homework questions are reading those
mailing lists and would
be able to identify all homework questions
without a doubt.
So we've seen them all, don't bother
trying to
get the answers to your homework on
mailing lists.
Don't ever email multiple mailing lists at
once.
So this is little bit annoying, because,
people will be
subscribed to different mailing lists and
will be getting your message
more then one time.
It's useful to, it's important to figure
out which mailing list is the most
appropriate
mailing list for your question and then
send
the message to that mailing list or forum.
And then lastly, don't ask others to debug
your code without
giving some sort of hint as to what the
problem might be.
So it's, it's very difficult when a person
posts a long listing of code
and says, there is a problem in
here somewhere, I don't know where, please
help.
It's better
to give to kind of specify where you think
the problem is
and what you're trying to do so that
everyone can save some time.
So this is just the very brief case study
on using a recent post to the R-devel
mailing list.
R-devel mailing list is an email list for
people who are doing development work in
R.
So either they're developing packages or
they're
making modifications to the R source code
itself.
And so the subject was, you could see
from the subject that it's going to be a
problem.
The subject is large data set dash
confused.
So right away that much information
here to go on.
It's not clear what the problem is.
And the message just says I'm trying to
load
a data set into R, but I'm completely
lost.
This is probably due to, mostly to the
fact that I'm on
a complete R noob, but it's got me stuck
in a research project.
So you have to ask yourself, what do I
know about this persons problem from
reading this message?
And the truth is very little.
And so the response was somewhat
predictable.
Basically the
first person response said, yes you are
lost.
And then there is a pointer to the posting
guide
which everyone should read before sending
email through the mailing list.
And then also a list of manuals.
And so, here you can see that one round of
email was immediately
wasted because probably the answer to the
question was in one of the manuals.
And so, and the user didn't specify
whether he or she had already done that.
So, in terms of what went wrong with this
little exchange, first
of course the question was sent to simply
the wrong mailing list.
The R-devel mailing list is for
development questions and for more
sophisticated programmers.
It's not really mailing list for questions
as this person stated noobs.
So that question really should have gone
to the R
help mailing list where it would have been
better received.
However, in addition to that, the email
subject was very vague.
It was not clear
what the problem was.
The question itself was very vague.
There was no reproducible example there.
There was nothing, there's not possible
for other people who
were reading the e-mail to reproduce what
that person's problem was.
And further, and there was no evidence
that
any effort was made to solve the problem.
So there's no evidence that they searched
the web or checked the manuals or
or experimented with the problem or
anything
like that or even looked at the forums.
So the end result was a complete recipe
for
disaster and there were, it was likely
that this
person did not get the answer to their
question.
So, a couple places to turn for this
course, first
of all the class discussion board I think
will be the
most useful because your fellow students
can help you out
there and I can respond to you on the
discussion board.
Outside of class there's the R help
mailing list which I just described.
And you can post to this mailing list as
long, and it's useful to
of course follow all the rules that we
talked about just now a bit.
And depending on what other projects you
might be working on there are other
project-specific
mailing lists for other types of software.
And so this talk was inspired by Eric
Raymond's
posting called How to ask questions the
smart way.
And I encourage you to read that.
It's much longer.
It has a lot of other useful tips.