Hi, everyone.
I just want to introduce a experimental
feature that
we've, that we've developed for the R
programming class.
It's called Statistics with Interactive R
Learning or SWIRL for short.
And it's, and it was developed by Nick
Carchedi, who's
a student here at the Johns Hopkins
department of bio-statistics.
This is a system that allows you to kind
of interactively learn R at your own pace.
And it will walk you through a, a bunch of
lessons about different
aspects of the R language and you can kind
of practice as you go.
So, rather than kind of watching a lecture
and then,
you know, doing an assignment and kind of
doing things
piece by piece, you can actually work on R
right
in the R console in, in a kind of guided
way.
Rather than kind of just figuring things
out on your own.
So, I think this, the SWIRL modules are
really helpful
and I encourage you to try to walk through
them.
If you decide to complete them you'll get
you'll
get a little extra credit through the
programming assignment.
But the, the modules are absolutely not
required.
They are totally optional.
And so, you don't have to worry about
doing them.
You can still do perfectly well in the
class without doing the SWIRL modules.
Nevertheless, I encourage you to try it
out.
I think it'll be a lot of fun.